Sixty knots?
No way, Barnes.
The Reds don’t have
anything that fast.
Checked it twice.
I mean, it’s a real unique signature...
no cavitation,
no reactor noise.
It doesn’t even sound like screws.
What the hell is it?
I’ll tell you what it’s not.
It’s not one of ours.
Sir, contact changing to heading
two-one-four.
Speed...
eighty knots.
Eighty knots.
Still diving.
Depth, 900--
Depth, 900 feet.
Port clearance, a 150 feet
from the cliff wall, sir.
- It’s getting tight in here.
- Yeah?
We can still give ’em a haircut.
Helm, come right to... oh-six-niner.
Down five degrees.
Coming right oh-six-niner.
Down five degrees, aye.
Port side clearance 120 feet
narrowing to 75.
Sir, we have a proximity warning light.
It’s too damn close.
We gotta back off.
Sir, range to contact, 200.
Contact just jinked to bearing two-six-oh
and accelerated to...
to 130 knots, sir.
Nothin’ goes a 130.
Sir, range to contact,
100 yards.
Eighty yards, sir!
Sixty!
It’s turbulence.
We’re in its wake.
Helm, all stop.
Full right rudder.
Hydraulics failure.
Planes not responding, sir.
Hydraulics restored, sir.
Oh, my God.
Fire in sonar!
Collision alarm!
Fire control to sonar!
Let’s get out of here!
- Lighten her up, Charlie!
- Torpedo room is flooded, sir!
Blow all tanks!
Blow all the tanks! Blow everything!
- All back full!
- Answering, all back full.
Give me a damage report.
What’s our depth?
Passing 1,400, sir.
Main’s forward tanks
are ruptured!
Still descending, sir.
1,450.
Passing 1,500, sir.
Still descending.
- We’re too deep to pump auxiliaries.
- Passing 1,550, still descending, sir.
- We’re losin’ her.
- Passing 1,600, sir,
- and still descending. Passing 1,650.
- Launch the buoy.
- Passing 1,700, sir.
- Launching!
Give me your hand! Come on!
Benthic Explorer. Salvor One on final. Over.
Copy you, Salvor One.
This is Benthic Explorer.
You’re cleared to land.
Hey. They’re coming.
This...
could get pretty ugly.
Yeah. It does not look good at all.
Oh, no.
Look who’s with ’em.
Queen bitch of the universe.
Sonny, how you doing?
I got two more welds
on this bypass valve.
No light from the surface.
How deep are they?
McBride?
1,700 feet.
I need them to go below 2,000.
No problem. They can do that.
So, that’s it?
You just cheerfully turn the whole thing over
to the goon squad?
Look, I was told to cooperate.
I’m cooperating.
Kirkhill, you’re pathetic.
Get Brigman on the line.
Deepcore, this is Benthic.
Man, if Bud goes along with this,
they’re gonna have to shoot her
with a tranquilizer gun.
Roger.
Hippy, get me Bud.
Catfish, get them old bones up here
and give me a hand.
Hang on. I’ll be up there in a second.
Hey, you guys are
milkin’ that job.
Yeah, it’s ’cause we love freezin’ our
butts off out here for you so much.
- Hey, Bud!
- Yeah?
Hippy’s on the bitch-box.
It’s a call from topside.
Benthic company man.
- Kirkhill?
- Yeah.
That guy don’t know his butt
from a rat hole.
Hey, Harry, do me a favor, will ya?
Square away this mud hose.
Get rid of some of these empty sacks. This
place is startin’ to look like my apartment.
You got it, boss.
Bud, pick up
the topside line, urgent.
I’m comin’. I’m comin’.
Geez, keep your pantyhose on.
Brigman here.
Yeah, Kirkhill, what’s goin’ on?
Yeah, I’m calm.
I’m a calm person.
Is there some reason
why I shouldn’t be calm?
What?
All right, I’m on land speed now.
Hey, can you get that goddamn
hippy shit music off the com line, please?
I’m almost done with the shut-off valve.
I’m right behind you
with the next fitting.
Hang on a second.
- Okay, give it to me.
- Here you go.
Thanks, sweetie.
All divers, drop what you’re doin’.
Everybody out of the pool.
I mean everybody, right now.
Sonny, One Night, let’s go.
Damn it. We just got out here.
There was a time
when I would’ve asked why.
- Get a move on!
- Shit, woman!
Deepcore, Deepcore,
this is Flatbed preparing to surface.
Roger, Flatbed. Come on up.
All rig personnel,
assemble at the moon pool.
Everybody get to sub-bay ASAP.
Come on.
Get his hat off.
Take it off.
What the hell’s goin’ on?
How come we got recalled?
- Hell if I know.
- I got it.
So, what’s the drift, podner?
Why are we up?
Just follow standard procedure.
Flog the dog till somebody
tells you what’s happening.
- What’s the story, boss?
- Folks, listen up!
We’ve just been told to shut down the hole
and prepare to move the rig.
- What?
- We’ve received an invitation to...
“cooperate in a matter
of national security”.
- Shit.
- Now you know as much as I do.
Get your gear off and get to control.
We’ve got a briefing in ten minutes.
Come on, come con!
Let’s move it.
At 09:22 local time today,
an American nuclear submarine,
the U.S.S Montana,
with 156 men aboard,
went down about 22 miles from here.
- Damn.
- Been no contact with the sub since then.
The cause of the incident
is not known.
Your company’s authorized the Navy’s use
of this facility for a rescue operation...
code-named Operation Salvor.
You want us to search for the sub?
No. We know where it is.
But she’s in 2,000 feet of water
and we can’t reach her.
We need divers to enter the sub
and search for survivors, if any.
Don’t you guys have
your own stuff for this?
By the time we get our rescue submersibles
here, the storm front will be on us.
You can get your rig in under the storm
and be on-site in 15 hours,
and that makes you
our best option right now.
Why should we risk our butts
for something like this?
I have been authorized
to offer you all special bonuses,
equivalent to three times normal dive pay.
Yes, sir, buddy!
Hell, for triple time, I’d eat Beany.
They could set me on fire
and put me out with horse piddle.
I don’t know what deal
you guys made with the company,
but my people are not qualified for this.
- We’re oil workers.
- This is a paycheck, man!
Shut up! Hold it down.
This is Lieutenant Coffey.
He’ll transfer down to you with a SEAL team
and supervise the operation.
You can send whoever you like, Commodore,
but I’m the tool-pusher on this rig,
and when it comes to
the safety of these people,
there’s me and then there’s God,
understand?
If things get dicey,
I’m pullin’ the plug.
I think we’re all
on the same wavelength, Brigman.
Now, let’s get the wellhead uncoupled,
shall we?
All right,
let’s get ready to move.
Let’s take it
about five degrees left, all right?
Roger. Five degrees left, Bud.
Plot these numbers to our position. I need
to know when the leading edge’s gonna hit.
Well, it’s official,
sports fans. They’re calling it
Hurricane Frederick.
And it’s gonna be making our lives
real interesting in a few hours.
Fred, huh?
I don’t know, man. I think hurricanes
should be named after women, don’t you?
I can’t believe
you’re letting them do this.
Hi, Lins.
I thought you were in Houston.
I was.
Now I’m here.
- Only here isn’t where I left it, is it, Bud?
- Wasn’t up to me.
Jesus! We were that close to proving
a submersible drilling platform could work.
I can’t believe you let them grab my rig!
- Your rig?
- My rig.
I designed the damn thing.
Yeah, and Benthic Petroleum paid for it,
so as long as they’re holding the pink slip,
I go where they tell me.
I had a lot riding on this,
and they bought you, didn’t they?
More like rented you cheap!
I’m switchin’ off now.
- Bye-bye.
- Oh, okay,
Virgil, you wiener!
You never could stand up to a fight.
Bye-bye.
“Virgil”?
God, I hate that bitch.
Probably shouldn’t have
married her then, huh?
Try to get it settled!
Roger, Cab Three. You’re clear to launch.
- Hang on, gentlemen.
- She’s clear!
Touchdown.
Crowd goes wild.
Explorer, this is Cab Three.
We are styling.
- How are you boys doing back there?
- Great.
Explorer, this is Cab Three.
Starting our descent along the umbilical.
- Roger that, Cab Three. Good luck.
- Luck is not a factor.
One Night, how you doin’?
I got white-line fever, baby.
Yeah, I heard that.
♪ Driven by the snow ♪
♪ Drunk and dirty
but don’t you know ♪
♪ That I’m still ♪
♪ Willin’ ♪
♪ Out on the road
late last night ♪
♪ I seen my pretty Alice
in every headlight ♪
♪ Dallas ♪
♪ Dallas Alice ♪
♪ And I’ve been from Tucson
to Tucumcari ♪
♪ Tehachapi to Tonopah ♪
♪ Driven every kind of rig
that’s ever been made ♪
♪ Driven the back roads
so I wouldn’t get weighed ♪
♪ And if you give me ♪
♪ Weed ♪
♪ Whites and wine ♪
♪ And you show me a sign ♪
♪ Then I’d be willin’ ♪
♪ To be movin’ ♪
Deepcore, Deepcore,
this is Cab Three on final approach.
Roger, Cab Three.
Is that you, Lindsey?
None other.
Oh, no.
Howdy, boys.
Hey, Lindsey.
I’ll be damned.
Y’all shouldn’t be down here, sweet thing.
Might ruin your stockings.
The bad news is
we got eight hours in this can blowing down.
And the worse news is it’s...
gonna take us three weeks
to decompress later.
We’ve all been fully briefed,
Mrs. Brigman.
Just don’t call me that, okay?
I hate that.
All right.
Well, what would you
like us to call you?
“Sir”?
Okay, here we go.
Y’all start equalizin’...
now.
Let’s watch each other
closely for signs of HPNS.
High-Pressure Nervous Syndrome.
Muscle tremors, usually in the hands first.
- Nausea, increased excitability.
- Disorientation.
♪ And a partridge in a pear tree ♪
About one person in twenty
can’t handle it.
They just go “buggo”.
Look, they’ve all made runs to this depth.
They’re checked out.
No, I understand that.
What I’m saying is that it’s impossible
- to predict just who’s susceptible--
- They’re checked out.
- These guys are SEALs?
- Yeah.
These guys ain’t so tough.
I’ve fought guys
plenty tougher than them.
Now we get to hear
how you could’ve been a contender?
Hey!
Hey! Hey!
- You see this?
- Yeah.
They used to call this “the Hammer”.
Y’all are done to a turn
and ready to serve.
Everybody okay?
- They’re really very sweet.
- Oh, yeah.
Hey! I don’t remember putting a wall here.
How you doing, Jammer?
- Pretty good. How are you, little lady?
- I’m okay.
- I want a full check on that gear.
- Yes, sir.
These guys are about as much fun
as a tax audit.
You got that right.
Hippy, you’re gonna
give that rat a disease.
Hi, Lins.
Well, well.
Mrs. Brigman.
Not for long.
You never did like
being called that, did you?
Not even when it meant something.
- Is that One Night in Flatbed?
- Yeah. Who else?
Here. Say hi.
Hey, One Night, it’s Lindsey.
Oh, hi, Lindsey.
Bud, obstacle avoidance is showin’ a rise
out about 100 meters. What do you want to do?
Copy, Bud?
I can’t believe you were
dumb enough to come down here.
Now you’re stuck here for the storm.
That was dumb, hot-rod, real dumb.
I didn’t come down here
to fight with you.
Yeah? Well...
then why did you come down?
You need me.
Nobody knows the systems on this rig
better than I do.
Once you’re disconnected from Explorer, you’re
on your own for how long this storm lasts.
What if something was to happen
after the surface support clears off?
- What would you have done?
- Wow, you’re right.
Us poor, dumb old boys
might’ve had to think for ourselves.
It could have been a disaster.
- Wanna know what I think?
- Jesus, look where this thing is set.
You wanna know what I think?
Not particularly.
- I think you were worried about me.
- Then that must be it.
No, seriously, I think you were.
Come on.
It’s okay.
It’s okay. You can admit it.
I was worried...
about the rig.
I’ve got over four years
invested in this project.
Yeah. You only had
three years invested in me.
Well, you have to have priorities.
It’s kind of messy, but...
I guarantee you,
it’s the only bunk that won’t be occupied.
You can get a couple hours rest
before we get there.
What are you still wearing that for?
I don’t know.
The divorce ain’t final.
I forgot to take it off.
I haven’t worn mine in months.
Yeah.
Well, what’s-his-name wouldn’t like it.
The Suit.
Do you always
have to call him that?
“The Suit”?
Makes you sound like such a hick.
His name is Michael.
How is Michael anyway?
Mr. Brooks Brothers.
Mr. BMW.
Still seeing him?
No.
No, I haven’t seen him
in a few weeks.
Terribly sorry.
What happened?
- Why are you doing this? Why?
- What?
This is none of your business.
It’s not a part of your life anymore.
I’ll tell you what happened.
You woke up one morning
in those satin sheets.
You rolled over and there was
this good-looking guy,
well-groomed,
expensive watch on.
And you realized,
“This guy never makes me laugh.”
That’s it, Bud. That’s it.
Aren’t you clever?
Jesus, you’re clever. You should start
your own talk show or something! Ask Dr. Bud,
advice to the lovelorn
from 300 fathoms.
Thank you. Thank you.
Oh, shit.
I’m cuttin’ you loose, Bud.
Okay, One Night, stay clear.
We’re settin’ her down.
Touchdown!
This is us. We’re sitting
right on the edge of the Cayman Trough.
This is the Montana,
300 meters away,
70 meters below us.
We think she slid down the wall,
and now sits here on this outcropping.
So, we’re gonna have to drop
straight down...
here.
This tell us how much
radiation we’re gettin’?
Whoa whoa whoa!
I’m not going near radiation. No way!
Aw, Hippy, you pussy.
What good is the money?
Six months later, your dick drops off.
We’ll take readings as we go.
If the reactor’s breached, or the warhead’s
released any radioactive debris,
we’ll just back off.
It’s that simple.
- Oh, okay.
- Hippy is not going, so...
McWhirter,
you can run “Little Geek”.
Goddamn it. You know McWhirter
can’t run an ROV worth shit!
- Then you’d better go.
- I’ll go.
- Good!
- What is your problem, huh?
On this dive,
you’ll do absolutely nothing
without direct orders from me,
and you’ll follow those orders
without discussion.
Is that clear?
All right. I want everyone to finish prep
and ready to get wet in 15 minutes.
One of you guys give me a hand, okay?
Let’s get suited up.
Guys, guys.
Hold it a second.
- Before you jump in there...
- Hold it!
...I’ve to charge the main batteries.
- Okay, here we go.
- This goes to the right--
Look...
it’s 3:00 a.m.
These guys are running on bad coffee
and about four hours of sleep.
Maybe you could think about
cutting them some slack.
I can’t afford slack.
Hey, you come on my rig.
You don’t talk to me.
You start orderin’ my people around.
It’s not gonna work.
You got to know how to
handle these people.
We got a way
of doin’ things around here.
Right now, I’m not interested
in your way of doing things.
Just get your team ready to dive.
These guys got no sense of humor.
Bud, you know your hand is blue?
Finler, why don’t you just shut up
and put your gear on?
Keep it coming.
- Hippy, throw me one of them cyalumes.
- Yeah, sure.
- Good. Good.
- Excuse me.
- What is all this stuff?
- Fluid-breathing system. We just got them.
- You use it when you go really deep.
- How deep?
- Deep.
It’s classified.
You breathe liquid,
so you can’t get compressed.
- The pressure doesn’t get you.
- You mean you got liquid in your lungs?
- Oxygenated fluorocarbon emulsion.
- Bullshit.
Check this out.
- Can I borrow your rat?
- What are you doin’?
- Hey, no, no, no!
- You’re gonna kill her!
- It’s okay. I’ve done this myself.
- Oh, man! You’re just drowning her?
She’s gonna be fine.
I’ve breathed this myself.
It’s gonna be fine.
No, man. She’s gonna drown!
Look! She’s freakin’ out!
- Just a normal adjustment period.
- Does this look normal to you?
- She’s gonna drown!
- He’s taking the fluid into his lungs.
He’s taking the fluid into his lungs.
There he goes.
There’s a bit of anxiety here.
Now he’s starting to relax.
He’s breathing fine.
See his chest moving?
He’s getting plenty of oxygen.
Damn rat’s breathin’ that shit.
That is, no bullshit, hands down,
the goddamnedest thing I ever saw.
See, the fluid’s harder to
push in and out than air.
It’s a little more work to breathe,
but he’s doing fine.
- He’s diggin’ it.
- She’s doin’ it. She ain’t diggin’ it.
All right, let her out, now. Now!
Okay. All right.
Okay, now we let the fluid
drain from his lungs.
All right. Give her here.
Give her. Give her.
Here’s your rat.
- See? He’s fine.
- It’s a she.
Going over the wall.
Coming to bearing 0-6-5.
Flatbed, you on line?
10-4, Lindsey.
We read you loud and clear.
Starting our descent.
Divers, how you doin’?
Everybody’s okay so far.
Hang on, boys.
It’s all downhill from here.
Hey, how deep’s
the drop-off here?
This here’s the bottomless pit, baby,
two-and-a-half miles straight down.
Cab Three, it’s Bud. You on line?
Cab Three, check.
I’m right behind you.
Cab One, do you see it yet?
Magnetometer’s twitching,
but I don’t see anything yet.
Hang on. I want to test my strobes.
Cab One, do you have a visual?
- Cab One, do you copy?
- Yeah.
Roger that.
Found it.
Cab One, radiation readings.
Neutron counter’s not showing much.
All right. Just continue forward
along the hull.
Copy that. Continuing forward.
You want me to get
shots of everything?
Roger that. Document as much as you can,
but please keep moving.
Remember, we’re on a tight timeline.
Copy that.
Coming up to the midship’s hatch.
Do you see it, Cab Three?
Yeah, roger. I got it.
- How do you want me?
- Just hold above it.
- Roger. Holding.
- Okay, it’s all yours, Lieutenant.
All right, A-team. Let’s do it.
Okay, Perry, Hippy,
let’s get that ROV launched.
Okay, we’re on it, Boss.
Go.
Little Geek is on the case.
Monk here, sir.
We got the midship’s outer hatch open.
Entering escape trunk.
Entering hatch looks intact.
It’s flooded.
All right, I’m gonna open her up.
Okay, get in there.
Roger. Somebody get on that tether.
Got it.
Sorry about this, little buddy,
but better you than me. Know what I mean?
- Coffey, these are the missile hatches?
- That’s right.
Looks like a couple of
the hatches have sprung.
Radiation’s nominal.
Warheads must still be intact.
How many are there?
24 Trident missiles.
8 MIRVs per missile.
That’s 192 warheads, Coffey.
How powerful are they?
Your MIRV is a tactical nuke.
50 kilotons nominal yield,
say, five times Hiroshima.
Jesus Christ.
It’s World War III in a can.
Let’s knock off the chatter, people.
- I’m heading into the reactor compartment.
- Any reading?
It’s twitchin’, but it’s below the line
you said was safe.
All right. Let’s get in there.
Flatbed, drop down starboard
and stay along the cliff edge.
Okay, copy that.
Keep heading for the bow.
Okay, Flatbed, this looks good.
Just set it down here.
- We’re solid.
- Let’s go.
All right. Let’s go.
Okay, let’s just take it
slow and easy goin’ in.
Don’t take any chances.
Where are we, Coffey?
This is the forward berthing compartment.
This way.
You guys okay? Cat? Jammer?
- Right behind you, Bud.
- Check your gauges.
- How’s your O₂?
- I’m okay.
Yeah, gauges are good.
Okay, 16 minutes to go.
Jammer, your CO₂ is up.
- Breathe slower, buddy.
- I’m okay.
Come on. Let’s keep up.
All right. Up this way
to the control center.
- It’s jammed. Give me a hand.
- Get up here with that pry bar.
It’s moving! Pull!
Jesus!
All right. We knew we were gonna see this.
Just move on.
- Jesus!
- Come on, Jammer. Let’s go.
Okay, let’s stay cool.
Everybody stay cool.
We can’t help these guys,
but we might find somebody further in.
Stay here.
Hey, Jammer. You okay?
- How you guys doin’?
- I’m dealin’.
Triple time sounded like
a lot of money, Bud. It ain’t.
We’re here.
Let’s get ’er done, okay.
Brigman,
take your men and continue aft.
Split up into two teams.
Come on. Let’s get moving.
We head back in 14 minutes.
Let’s go.
You okay, Jammer?
Yeah, fine.
- What’s this?
- Should be the missile launch control center.
- Don’t touch anything.
- No, no, no, no, no.
This way.
Right behind you.
- You still with me, Jammer?
- Where are we?
Missile compartment.
Those are the launch tubes.
Shit! Shit, shit, shit!
Hey, Jammer.
Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey! You okay?
Deep and slow, big guy.
Deep and slow.
Just breathe easy.
- Everybody’s dead! They’re all dead.
- Okay.
- I’m taking you back out. Let’s go.
- No!
I’m okay. I’m okay.
- I just can’t go any further in.
- Okay, Jammer. No problem. Stay right here.
I’ve got to check out
this compartment, all right?
We’ll stay in voice contact.
You hold on the end of this rope here.
You have any problem whatsoever,
- you tug twice.
- I got it.
Pull it hard. Five more minutes.
Just relax, all right? You’ll be okay.
- Okay.
- Be right back.
You still readin’ me okay, big guy?
Read you fine, Bud.
Okay,
just a few more minutes.
There’s a couple compartments up ahead
that might have air.
- Okay, no problem.
- We got to be sure, right?
Hang on, Jammer.
You just hold on to that--
Shit!
Bud?
Bud, can you hear me?
Goddamn it!
Oh, Jesus!
Bud, is that you?
Hang on, Jammer.
Lew, Cat,
hurry up, on the double!
I’m on my way.
Jammer!
- What’s the problem?
- He’s convulsing!
It’s his mixture. Too much oxygen.
Got to get the O₂ cut down!
Turn him over!
Crank it down, man!
You’re losin’ him!
All right. We got to get him out of here.
Let’s go. Let’s move it.
Easy, big fella.
That’s it.
One Night, do you see the divers?
Are they out yet?
Negative, Lindsey.
Haven’t seen hide nor hair.
Let’s give them two minutes more max,
and then I’ll sound the diver recall--
Lindsey, do you copy?
Meet me at Flatbed. This is a diver emergency.
Lins, do you copy?
Yeah, copy you, Bud.
I’m on my way.
Look, I’m just a medic,
which is mostly
about patchin’ holes.
This type of thing, it’s...
there’s not much I can do.
A coma could last hours or days.
So, you didn’t get anything
on these cameras.
No. I didn’t get a picture of it.
- What about the video?
- No.
We lost power right then.
Look, I just don’t want to
talk about this, okay?
Fine. Be that way.
Look, I don’t know
what I saw, Bud, okay?
Coffey wants to call it a Russian submersible,
fine, it’s a Russian submersible.
No problem.
Yeah, but you think
it was somethin’ else.
What?
One of ours?
No.
Well, whose then?
Come on, Lindsey, talk to me.
Look, Jammer saw something down there,
something that
scared the hell out of him.
His mixture got screwed up.
Jammer panicked.
He pranged his regulator,
and his mixture got screwed up.
But what did he see
that made him panic?
Well, what do you think he saw?
I don’t know.
- Did any of you see it?
- No, sir. The Brigman woman saw it.
It could have been
a Russian bogey.
CINCLANTFLT’s gonna go apeshit.
Two Russian attack subs, a Tango and a Victor,
were tracked within 50 miles of here.
Now they don’t know
where the hell they are.
Okay.
I haven’t got any choice.
I’m confirming
you to go to Phase Two.
You’ll recover one warhead,
arm it
and wait for
further instructions.
- We got a problem with that?
- Negative, sir.
Come on!
- What did he say?
- Turn it up, bozo!
...early reports that
the Montana encountered
a Soviet fast-attack sub
prior to its sinking,
and the Kremlin
continues to deny any involvement.
Oh, that’s us.
That’s us, man.
Benthic Petroleum are apparently
participating in the recovery operation,
but we have little information
about their involvement.
Bullshit. We want names.
- That’s the Explorer. We’re famous.
- Shh, quiet.
There is a tremendous amount of activity.
With Cuba only 80 miles away,
the massive buildup
of American forces...
has drawn official protest
from Havana and Moscow.
Russian and Cuban trawlers,
undoubtedly surveillance vessels,
have been circling the area,
and Soviet aircraft have repeatedly...
- This sucks.
- ...been warned away.
Hippy, what’s the matter with you?
What’s the matter with me? Nothing.
We’re just in the middle of some
big-time international incident,
- like the Cuban missile crisis or something.
- Figured that out for yourself, did you, Hip?
You know, we got Russian subs
creeping around.
Anything goes wrong down here,
they could say whatever they want.
- Hippy, will you just relax?
- Give our folks medals.
You’re makin’ the women nervous.
- Cute, Virgil.
- Those SEALs ain’t telling us diddly.
- Somethin’ is going on!
- Come on, come on.
Hippy, you think
everything’s a conspiracy.
Everything is.
Hurry up!
Coffey’s splitting with Flatbed.
I showed him how to work the controls,
and they’re outta here.
- Didn’t you tell him we need it now?
- He didn’t pay any attention!
- Where the hell is he taking it?
- I have no idea!
Shit!
Coffey! Come back!
We need the big arm
to unhook the umbilical.
There’s a goddamn hurricane comin’!
- He switched off.
- It’s unbelievable.
Go back down.
Tell those men
to get below and stay there.
We need to get unhooked
and get out of here now.
All right, do it then.
No problem, except your boys
went sightseeing with Flatbed.
My people need Flatbed
to get unhooked at their end.
- Back in two hours.
- Two hours?
We’re gonna get the shit kicked out of us
by our pal Fred in two hours.
- Set cold tab fitting to 200 PSI.
- Set.
There she goes.
She’s breaking loose. Bringing her up.
Okay.
All right.
Get clear of the hatch. Keep goin’ with it.
Keep goin’. That’s it, up.
Sir,
the missile looks intact.
Little is known at this hour
about the events leading up to the collision.
The US Navy guided missile cruiser Appleton
apparently struck
the Soviet Udaloy class destroyer...
in low visibility conditions.
In violent seas, little hope remains
for over 100 Russian crewmen
still missing after
the sinking an hour ago.
Soviet military spokesmen
have claimed that the collision
constituted an unprovoked attack.
- This was denied by state department...
- This is big time.
...who said that Captain Michael Sweeney
was acting correctly--
Okay, it’s clear.
It’s all yours, sir.
- I’m gonna swing it away and drop it.
- Check. Okay.
Bypass the ground connection
on the separation sequencer.
- Got it?
- Separation sequencer disconnected.
Remove explosive bolts one through six
in counterclockwise sequence.
Check. Removing bolt one.
Negotiators have walked out of
the Strategic Arms Limitation Talks
in protest
over the incident this morning--
The sudden deterioration of relations
with the United States and the Soviet--
Soviet buildup of tanks and aircraft
has continued.
Sometime this morning, all US and NATO
military forces have been put on full alert.
It’s on every channel.
Well, you just
feel so helpless.
You can see it coming,
but what can you do? What can anyone do?
Hey, I mean, they love their kids, too.
So, why are we doin’ this?
If it happens, it happens.
There’s nothing
I can do about it, right?
I just don’t think about it.
All right. Let’s get their gear off!
Then clear the sub.
We got to get it out of here!
Come on. Let’s go. Let’s move it.
One Night, you’re up.
Get ready to roll, baby.
- Don’t touch that. Just back away.
- Excusez moi.
Hey, Coffey,
we are a little pressed for time.
Prick.
This ain’t no drill, slick.
Make me proud.
Piece of cake, baby.
- What’s the problem, One Night?
- All hell must be breaking loose up there.
This cable’s pissin’ me off.
- I can’t get a grip on it.
- Well, keep tryin’, baby. Just keep tryin’.
Son of a bitch!
Shit! We got a problem!
- What’s going on?
- We’re losing number two thruster!
Bearing’s going!
It’s not holding.
We’re swinging out of position here!
Goddamn it!
Jesus!
Shit!
- The rig is movin’!
- Yeah, I can see that. Topside!
Topside! Pay out some slack.
We’re gettin’ dragged.
- Down on number one winch! Down on one!
- We’re gettin’ dragged!
Bud, we’re headed
right for the drop-off.
What the hell?
We just lost all the topside feeds.
Shit! Get ’em on the UQC!
Bud!
- We lost the crane!
- Say again. What?
The crane! We’ve lost the crane!
It’s on its way down to you!
All right, everybody.
Everybody, rig for impact!
Close all the exterior hatches!
Let’s move it! Let’s go!
Go! Go! Go! Go!
- Wait, wait, wait!
- Get in here!
What the hell is goin’ on around here?
I don’t know.
You two help secure the rig. Let’s go.
One Night! One Night, you hear me? Get the
hell out of there! The crane’s comin’ down!
I’m okay. I’m clear, Bud.
I’ve got it. It’s headed straight for us.
Oh, shit.
- Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no.
- Oh, my God!
- Bud!
- Grab on to something!
Jesus!
- Battery room’s flooding! Let’s go!
- Cat, put that out!
- Bud!
- Yeah?
- Drill room’s floodin’!
- Get back down there!
Go! I’ll take the battery room.
Jesus!
Shit!
Get out of there!
Close the door! Seal the room!
Lindsey,
let’s get out of here!
Whoa!
- Hold this on me!
- Okay!
Lindsey! Lindsey!
I got it!
Let’s get the hell out of here!
Let’s go!
Let’s go! Get the door!
Get the door!
Jesus!
Bud! Bud!
Finler, cut the hose!
Cut the line to the motor!
I can’t open it from out here!
Finler, cut the hose!
Finler!
Hey! Hey!
- Come on, Sonny!
- Hey, Cat! Cat, help me out, man!
Hang on!
The hose! Cut the hose!
The line to the motor! Hurry up, man!
Come on, Cat!
Hurry!
Come on, Sonny, help me out!
Come on, push!
Come on, Sonny!
- Come on, Sonny! Let’s go!
- Come on! Let’s go! We gotta go! Go! Go!
Get outta here!
Come on, move it!
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Get the hatch, Cat!
Get the hatch!
You all right?
Everybody okay?
- Yeah.
- Oh, son of a bitch.
Oh, man.
Benthic Explorer, Benthic Explorer,
this is Deepcore. Do you read me?
this is Deepcore.
Do you read me? Over.
Forget it, Sonny. They’re gone, man.
- Mayday, mayday, mayday.
- Hey.
They’re gone.
Okay?
I just want to get out of this.
Just like to see my wife
one more time.
Well, all right,
then you’d better keep trying, huh?
Mayday, mayday, mayday.
This is Deepcore Two.
Do you read me?
Benthic Explorer, Benthic Explorer,
do you read me?
This is Deepcore 2. Over.
Mayday, mayday, mayday.
This is Deepcore 2.
Do you read me? Over.
Hey, Jammer.
- You got the shakes.
- I know what I got.
I’ll deal with it, all right?
I’ll deal with me.
You deal with yourself.
Find your buddy?
- No.
- Tighter. Tighter.
- Brigman.
- What?
I was under orders.
I had no choice.
How’s it goin’, Cat?
What’s the scoop, ace?
Well, I can get power
to this module in sub-bay...
if I reroute these buses,
but I gotta get past the mains,
which are a total meltdown.
Bud, there won’t be enough
to run the heaters.
In a few hours, this place
is gonna be as cold as a meat locker.
What about O₂?
Yeah, well, brace yourself.
If we close off the sections we’re not using,
we have about maybe 12 hours’ worth.
Storm’s gonna last
a lot longer than 12 hours.
Yeah, well,
I can maybe extend that. Maybe.
There’s some storage tanks outboard,
next to the wrecked module.
I’ll have to go outside, though,
and tie onto them.
Hey, Lins.
- Lins.
- Yeah?
I’m glad you’re here.
Yeah.
I’m not.
Hey. Found Cab Three.
Deader than dogshit, boss.
That girder went
right through the brainpan.
Yeah, I see that.
- Where are you?
- Living quarters, level two.
Oh, geez.
That’s Perry.
That’s it, then.
Finler, McWhirter, Dietz and Perry.
Jesus.
We just leave ’em there?
Yeah, for now.
We got no choice.
Our first priority is to get
somethin’ to breathe.
Where are you now, Lins?
I’m under the starboard tri-module.
- Still with me, Hip?
- Right behind you, Lins.
How’s it look?
Well, you guys really screwed up my rig.
There’s a lot of wreckage out here.
Well, don’t get fouled.
Hey, hit me with that 9/16ths, okay?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
So...
there you were.
Yeah, there we were...
side by side on the same ship
for two months.
I’m a tool-pusher, and we’re
testing this automated derrick of hers.
We get back on the beach
and we’re living together.
Doesn’t mean you had to marry her.
Well, we were due to go back out
on the same ship. Six months of tests.
If you were married, you got a state-room.
Otherwise, it was bunks.
Okay. Good reason. Will you come over here,
and tighten this for me?
Then what?
Everything was all right there
for a while, you know.
Then she got promoted to chief engineer
on this thing a couple years ago.
She went front-office on you, man?
Yeah, well, you know Lindsey.
She’s just too damn aggressive...
Son of a bitch.
She didn’t leave me.
She just left me behind.
Bud, let me tell you somethin’.
She ain’t half as smart
as she thinks she is.
Get outta here.
Come on.
Let’s see those muscles.
Bingo. That’s one.
Two for two.
Hey. Hey.
Lindsey, do you read me? Over.
Copy you, Hippy.
What’s the matter?
Oh, shit. The power’s
jackin’ around with us again.
Lindsey, come back.
I just lost video.
Lindsey, are you th--
Hippy, do you copy?
Lins, you copy?
Oh, shit!
Oh, what the hell!
Hippy, do you copy?
Damn it.
Bud, do you copy? Over.
I seem to be having a problem here.
Shit.
Damn it.
- That’s a great shot, Lins.
- You drop your dive line?
Come on, you guys. Come on.
That’s the smaller one.
That’s the smaller one here.
- You can kinda see how it’s zigging around.
- Yeah, whatever it is.
I’m telling you what it is.
You’re just not hearing me.
- Now, Lindsey you--
- There is something down there.
Something not us.
You could be more...
specific.
- Something that zigs.
- Not us.
Not human.
Get it?
Something non-human,
but intelligent.
A non-terrestrial intelligence.
- A Non-Terrestrial Intelligence.
- Yes.
NTIs. Oh, man, that’s better than UFOs.
Oh, but that works too, huh?
Underwater Flying Objects.
Are we talking
little space friends here?
Hell, yeah! Hot rods of the Gods!
Right, Lins?
No, no, really.
It could be NTIs.
The CIA has known
about ’em forever.
They abduct people all the time, man.
- Would you do me a favor?
- There was once--
Stay off my side.
- Will you step into my office, please?
- Certainly.
I... come here.
- Jesus, Lins.
- Oh, Bud, come on.
Something important
is happening here.
I’m trying to
keep this under control.
I can’t allow you to create
this kind of hysteria.
Who’s hysterical?! Nobody’s hysterical!
All I’m saying is,
when you’re hangin’ on by your fingernails,
you don’t go
waving your arms around.
Look, I saw something. I’m not gonna
go in there and say I didn’t see it,
when I did. I’m sorry.
Please.
You are the most stubborn woman
I ever knew.
Yes. I am.
But I need you
to believe me right now.
Now, come on. Look at me. Come on.
Am I stressed out?
Do I have any symptoms of pressure sickness?
Tremors, slurred speech?
- No.
Bud, this is me, Lindsey. Okay?
You know me better
than anybody in the world.
Now watch my lips.
I saw these things.
I touched one of them, and...
it wasn’t some clunky steel can
like we would build.
It glided.
It was the most beautiful thing
I’ve ever seen.
Oh, God, I wish you’d been there.
It was a machine...
it was a machine, but it was alive.
It was like a...
like a dance of light.
Please. You have to trust me.
Now, I don’t think they mean us any harm.
I don’t know how I know that.
It’s just...
a feeling.
Geez.
I’m supposed to go on a feeling?
How can I go on a feeling?
- You think Coffey’s gonna go on “a feeling”?
- Well, we all see what we wanna see.
Coffey looks, and he sees Russians.
He sees hate and fear.
You have to look
with better eyes than that.
Please.
I can’t, Lins.
- No?
- I’m sorry.
All I want is 24-hour surveillance
on the exterior cam.
I’ve got six people, I’ve got--
Everybody, just stop.
All right,
I want a round-the-clock manning
of the sonar shack and the exterior cameras.
That Russian bogey comes back,
I don’t think we should be taking a nap.
Oh, give me a break, Coffey.
Those things live 3.5 miles down
in an abyssal trench.
Trust me, they’re not speaking Russian.
Have you finished the repairs
on the acoustical transmitter yet?
Nope.
Why not?
I was having my nails done.
Well, get it done.
Kiss my ass.
All right,
get somethin’ straight.
You people are under my authority.
- Look, podner.
- When I give you an ord--
Look, podner,
we don’t work for you,
we don’t take orders from you...
and we don’t much like you.
Hey, Cat.
Cat!
Yeah?
Why don’t you take
the first watch on sonar, okay?
Right on.
Sonny, you get a couple hours sleep,
then you spell Cat, all right?
Hippy, you handle
exterior surveillance.
One Night.
Would you do me a favor
and see if you can get that transmitter fixed?
- All right?
- Be a couple hours.
Got it.
All right.
Come on, A.J. Squared Away,
a little to the left.
What is that?
Oh, this is not happening.
Oh, man.
Look at me. I’m shakin’.
All right, wait, wait, wait.
And now...
here’s MIRV.
Come on, man.
What else could it be?
Why bring it here?
It’s gotta be some kind of emergency plan
to keep it away from the Russians, right.
Look, they hot-wire one of the nukes,
they use some kind of detonator
that they brought,
then they stick it back in the sub,
fry the whole thing up.
Bam! Slicker’n snot.
I’m tellin’ ya. And I’m not bein’ paranoi--
Hi, Lins.
Lins, will you just
wait a second.
Goddamn it, if you don’t do
something about it, I will!
Lindsey, we’ll do something about it!
Just wait a second!
- Lindsey.
- What?
- Just stop and think about this for a second.
You know, you’ve got some huevos
bringing that thing into my rig.
With all that’s going on up in the world,
you bring a nuclear weapon in here?
Mrs. Brigman...
Does this strike anyone
as particularly psychotic, or is it just me?
Mrs. Brigman, you don’t need to know
the details of our operation.
- It’s better if you don’t.
- You’re right. I don’t need to know.
What I need to know is that thing
is off this rig! Do you hear me, Roger Ramjet?
You’re becoming
a serious impediment to our mission.
Now, you either do an about-face
and walk out of here,
or I’ll have you escorted out.
I will not do an about-face
and get out of here.
Who the hell do you
think you’re talking to?
Emergency! Maintenance Room B!
Everybody move it!
- On the double!
- Now! Now!
In here! Come on! We’ve got trouble!
- Now! Come on!
- What’s goin’ on?
All right, all right, all right, all right!
What’s up? What’s happening?
All right, you let
her go, man. Do it.
Do it now!
Let her go.
The smartest thing you ever did.
- Coffey, you son of a bitch--
- Lindsey! Cool it.
- What’s the problem?
- Nothin’.
We were just leaving,
weren’t we?
We don’t need them.
We can’t trust them.
We may have to take steps.
We’re gonna have to take steps.
Lins, I want you to stay away
from that guy.
- I mean it.
- The guy is gone.
Did you see his hands?
What? He’s got the shakes?
Look, he’s operating on his own,
he’s cut off from
his chain of command,
he’s showing signs
of pressure-induced psychosis...
and he’s got a nuclear weapon.
So, as a personal favor to me, will you try
to put your tongue in neutral for a while.
I gotta tell you, I give this whole thing
a sphincter factor of about 9.5.
Look, you can just punch into his
primary guidance chip where you want him to go
and he’ll go there, right?
- No. Bad idea, Lindsey. Bad.
- Why? Hip, come on.
Because even if it could take
the pressure at that depth,
- which, I don’t think it can--
- Yeah?
Without the tether, know what
would happen if it got down there?
It would just sit like a-- Please.
It would just sit like a dumb shit.
Yeah, something would have to pass in front
of the camera for you to see anything.
I know. But we could get lucky, right?
So, we should go for it.
- I ought to talk to Bud about this.
- No way. This is between you and me.
We get proof,
and then we tell the others.
Hippy, look. If we can prove to Coffey
that there aren’t Russians down there,
maybe he’ll ease off the button a little bit.
I gotta tell you, man, that guy scares me more
than anything we’re gonna find down there.
He’s a goddamn A.J. Squared Away,
jarhead robot.
All right, gimme a couple hours
to see what I can do.
Great. Thanks.
How’s that?
Thanks.
Virgil, turn on your side.
All right, you’re all set, big guy.
Hey, I told you
to wipe that grin off your face.
Good night, little buddy.
Bud. Bud.
Bud! Get up.
What?
Cat.
- Cat!
- Hey!
Goddamn-- leave me alone.
Bud.
Wait. It’s okay.
Sweet Christ Almighty.
I think it likes you.
It’s trying to communicate.
That’s Bud.
- It’s wonderful!
- It’s me!
- No, no, no.
- Shh. It’s okay.
What is it?
Is it alive?
Lindsey, no.
Seawater.
Oh, man.
Come on. Come on!
- Hurry!
- Where the hell’s it goin’?
Hurry! I think it’s headed for “B” module.
Lins, you see it?
So, raise your hand if you think
that was a Russian water tentacle.
Lieutenant?
No? Well.
A breakthrough.
Hey, ace, you done impressin’ yourself?
No way that thing
could just be seawater.
They must have learned
to control water.
I mean, at a molecular level.
You know, they can plasticize it,
they can polymerize it,
do whatever they want to do with it.
They can put it under intelligent control.
Maybe...
their whole technology’s based on that.
- What?
- Controlling water.
Was it the same thing
that you saw the last time?
No.
You know, I don’t think
that that thing you saw was one of them.
- What are you talking about?
- I mean, I don’t think it was an NTI,
I think it was their version of an ROV,
like Big Geek.
- You mean they was just checkin’ us out?
- Yeah.
- How come?
- Curious, I suppose.
We’re probably the first people that have
ever seen one. Who’s been down this far?
Sure hope they
don’t judge the rest of us by him.
Went straight for the warhead,
and they think it’s cute.
You need to get some sleep.
We have no...
way of warning the surface.
And you know what that means?
It means whatever happens...
is up to us.
Us.
So, you think they’re
from down there originally,
or from...
you know...
I don’t know.
I think...
I think they’re from “you know”.
Some place with similar conditions...
cold, intense pressure.
Oh, man.
Happy as hogs in a waller
down there, prob’ly.
Sniff somethin’?
Did you, rat boy?
Hey! Hey! Hey! Come on!
Freeze! Don’t move!
That’s right.
- You okay, Hip?
- They’re using Big Geek
to take the bomb to the NTIs.
What?
- We set it up to go right to ’em.
- Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
Take this.
We’re going to Phase Three.
What? We don’t have orders for that!
I programmed Big Geek
to go down to the bottom of the trench
and shoot some video.
- Now they’ve got the warhead tied to it.
- Coffey?
- Linds--
- Coffey-- No. Come on.
Coffey, just think about
what you’re doing, okay, just one minute.
Just think about what you’re doing!
Get back!
This is something I’ve wanted to do
since we first met.
Easy. Easy.
Take it easy.
All right!
Into the kitchen! Let’s go!
- Move, partner!
- Get your damn hands off of me!
- Get in there!
- I know the way.
Your boss is fixin’
to pull the pin on 50 kilotons,
and we’re all gonna be ringside!
He’s having a full-on meltdown!
What’s the timer set for?
- Three hours.
- Shut up. Don’t talk.
Three hours?
We can’t get to minimum safe distance
in three hours.
We can’t go to Phase Three.
What about these people?
Shut up.
What’s the matter with you?
Everybody just stay calm.
The situation is under control.
Anybody touches that door,
kill ’em.
Schoenick, your lieutenant’s about to make
a real bad career move.
- The guy’s crazier than a shithouse rat!
- Schoenick!
- They’re trying to make contact!
- Can’t you see he’s lost it?
- Shut up!
- The shock wave’ll kill us.
- Quiet!
- It’ll crush this rig like a beer can.
- Shut up! What are you talkin’ about!?
- We gotta stop him.
Shut up!
This is not our mission.
We can’t detonate without orders.
Schoenick, please!
Schoenick, listen! He’s about to declare war
on an alien species
just when they’re trying to
make contact with us! Please!
- I don’t know. I think I’m reaching him.
- Yeah!
I’ll be damned.
- Jammer!
- Is everybody okay?
Oh, man!
- Don’t move, jarface!
- I’m the least of your problems.
- Take it easy, Hippy.
- I’m all right.
How you feelin’, big guy?
I’m okay, Bud, I...
I just...
I just figured I was dead back there
when I saw that angel comin’ for me.
Yeah, okay.
Yeah. Why don’t you
tell us about it later?
Come on.
He’s got it tied off with somethin’.
Ready?
We’re not gonna be able to budge it.
Now what?
This is the only door to sub-bay.
- What are you doing?
- I’m gonna swim to hatch six.
What?
I’m gonna get inside and I’m gonna
open the door from the other side.
Bud, this water is freezing.
Then I guess
you’d better wish me luck.
- Wish us luck.
- You comin’ along?
Looks that way.
- All right, Cat.
- Come on, Bud.
- In case I don’t die.
- This is insane.
Come on, Bud.
Let’s go, podner. I ain’t got all day.
Come on, yank on it.
Gonna have to...
Hafta go to the moon pool.
- It’s the only way.
- I can’t.
I can’t make it, podner.
I’m sorry.
Okay.
Okay, Cat.
You head on back, all right?
Shit!
- What is he doing?
- He can’t make it to the door.
He’s gonna try and take him out himself.
No. God, he couldn’t be that dumb.
That guy’s a trained killer.
No!
Coffey.
Coffey, listen...
Hey!
- Bud, you all right?
- Get him, Cat!
He’s dogged it, Bud.
We gotta get this off of here.
Come on, help me.
Pull the gripper! Pull it!
Cat, get the door.
Shit!
Come on!
- Shoot! Shoot!
- Are you all right?
The safety’s on!
Safety’s on!
Give me that!
Come on, let’s go!
Help me out!
- Give me a hand! Move it!
- One Night, what about Cab One?
Ready to launch.
Go! You’re better in these than I am!
You got air? Come on, come on.
You got air. You got air.
Shit.
Bud, get out of the way!
Shit!
Get in! Hurry up!
I’m comin’, baby.
Keep your pantyhose on.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Do you see Big Geek?
Right out in front.
- Oh, my God!
- Get after him!
- Okay, okay! Get on the arm.
- Ease up.
- To the left. A little more.
- You missed. Try it again.
- Stand steady.
- Okay.
- Grab it.
- Yeah. Got it!
- Pretty slick, Slick.
- Hold it really steady.
- Just hold it still.
- I am. I am.
Shit! We lost Geek!
- Where is he, Bud? Do you see him?
- I’ll take a look.
He’s comin’ up fast.
Step on it.
Shit!
- Go to the right. Swing to the right.
- Shit.
Keep movin’, baby.
Come here.
That son of a bitch.
Hard left, baby. Left, left, left!
Jesus Christ, lady.
Bud, if you think you can do any better,
then you’re welcome up here!
Son of a bitch.
- Is he right on us?
- Yeah, he is right on your ass.
- Okay. Okay.
- Where you goin’?
Hang on.
Deepcore, this is Cab One. Do you read?
Deepcore, Deepcore,
this is Cab One. Over.
I’m not getting any answer.
And we’re flooding
like a son of a bitch.
Yeah? You noticed?
You know, you did okay back there, Virgil.
I was fairly impressed.
Yeah, well, not good enough.
We still gotta catch Big Geek.
Yeah? Well, not in this thing.
Deepcore, Deepcore,
this is Cab One. Over.
Try it again.
Deepcore, this is Cab One.
We need as--
You all right?
Yeah.
- Well, that’s that.
- Yeah. Wonderful.
There’s light comin’ from somewhere.
It’s off to the right.
Yeah. That’s the rig.
It’s a good 60, 70 yards, I’d say.
Well, they’ll come after us.
Yeah, but it’s gonna take ’em
a while to get here.
We gotta get this flooding stopped.
- Can you see where it’s coming in?
- Yeah. Can you hold the lamp for me?
There’s a busted fitting
behind this panel.
Problem is, I don’t think
I can get to it.
- You got any tools?
- I don’t know. I’ll have to look around.
Yeah, well, I looked already.
Goddamn it, all I need
is a goddamn crescent wrench.
Come on.
Shit!
Son of a bitch!
Okay,
calm down, Bud.
- Calm down.
- Okay.
Okay.
- We gotta get you out of here.
- How?
- I don’t know how.
- All right, we’ve only got one suit.
- We’ve gotta come up with s--
- Oh, my God. I’m freezing.
Come here. Come here.
Give me your hands.
Listen, you’re smart. Think of somethin’.
Can’t you think of somethin’?
Okay, why don’t you swim back to the rig
and bring back another suit.
That’d take me about
seven, eight minutes to swim,
get the gear,
come back.
I wouldn’t make it. Look at this.
By the time I got back, you’d be...
- Okay. Okay. Let’s look around.
- Lins.
Just look a--
Oh, my God.
Is that working?
Shit.
- All right. All right, all right. Here.
- Bud, I’m getting cold.
You put this on.
No! Are you
growing gills all of a sudden?
Don’t argue with me, goddamnit.
Just put it on.
This is not an option,
so just forget about it.
Lindsey, shut up!
Shut up and put this thing on!
- If you’d be logical for one-- Please listen!
- Fuck logic!
Just listen to me for one second.
You’ve got the suit on, and you’re a
much better swimmer than I am, right?
- Yeah, maybe--
- Right? Yes. So, I’ve got a plan.
What’s the plan?
I drown, and you
tow me back to the rig.
No. No!
Yes. This water is only
a couple of degrees above freezing.
I’d go into deep hypothermia.
My blood’ll go like ice water.
Right?
My body systems will slow down.
They won’t stop.
- Lins--
- You tow me back and I can...
I can be revived after
maybe 10 or 15 minutes.
- Lins, put this on! You put it on!
- No! It’s the only way.
You just put this on!
Put this on. You know I’m right.
Please. It’s the only way.
You’ve got all the... stuff...
on the rig to do this.
Put this on.
Bud, please!
This is insane.
- Oh, my God. I know.
- You okay?
It’s the only way.
Here, hold this.
- Just hold on.
- Okay.
You can do this, you know.
You can do this.
- Oh, God, Lins, I...
- I know.
You can tell me later.
Oh, God!
This is maybe
not such a good idea!
Oh, my God!
Bud! No!
I can’t...
Oh, Bud, I’m scared!
No!
I got him! I got him!
- Where?
- Oh, my God. It’s Lindsey.
- Deepcore! Deepcore, do you read? Over.
- Yeah, we got you, Bud.
- We’re here.
- Go to the infirmary.
Get the cart oxygen, de-fib kit,
adrenaline in a 10cc syringe,
some heating blankets.
- You got all that?
- Got it. Over.
- Meet me at the moon pool! Make it fast!
- Now! Come on! Let’s go!
- Hippy, get the hot packs.
- Got ’em.
Here he comes!
- Get her up.
- Watch her head. Watch her head.
- I got it. I got it.
- Watch her feet.
Watch her head comin’ down.
Watch it.
Clear it out.
- Come on!
- Is she clear?
Get the de-fib ready.
Hurry up, Cat.
Okay, okay. Got it.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
3,000,
4,000,
- 5,000.
- Breathe!
1,000, 2,000, 3,000, 4,000--
No! Won’t work!
You gotta have bare skin, or it won’t work.
3,000, 4,000... Breathe.
Here.
- Is that right?
- I got it, Bud.
Well, do it!
Breathe!
- Come on, zap her.
- Clear!
Come on, baby. Aw, Christ!
- Nothing.
- Breathe!
- I’ll jack it up to 300.
- Do it again, One Night. Zap her again.
It’s going, it’s going. It’s charging.
Charging. Charging. Charging.
- Now!
- Clear!
- Anything?
- No pulse.
- Come on, baby.
- Just charging one more time.
Zap her again.
Come on!
- Come on!
- Clear!
God! No pulse.
Bud, it’s flat.
Goddamn, it’s flat.
One, two, three, four, five-one thousand.
One, two, three, four... breathe!
Breathe. Come on, baby.
1,000,
2,000,
3,000,
4,000...
Come on, baby.
1,000, 2,000,
3,000, 4,000, 5,000--
Come on, baby, breathe. Come on!
- 2,000, 3,000.
- Bud. Bud.
Bud? Bud.
It’s all over, man.
It’s all over.
I’m sorry.
No pulse.
No!
No! She has a strong heart!
She wants to live!
Come on, Lins!
Come on, baby!
Zap her again.
- Do it!
- Charging.
- Come on, baby.
- Clear.
Clear!
Get back!
Come on, breathe, baby.
Goddamn it, breathe!
Goddamn it, you bitch, you never
backed away from anything in your life!
Now fight!
Fight! Fight!
Right now! Do it!
Fight, goddamn it!
Fight! Fight! Fight!
Fight!
Lins. That’s it, Lindsey.
That’s it, Lins. You can do it.
That’s it, Lins. Come on back, baby.
Come on, you can do it, baby.
Lindsey.
Get her some air.
- Easy. Breathe easy.
- Look at that.
All right. All right.
You did it, ace! Huh?
Yeah! Yeah!
You did it, babe.
Easy. Breathe easy.
Watch her... Make sure--
make sure her heart’s doin’ okay.
Big boys don’t cry.
Remember?
Hi, lady.
Hi, tough guy.
- I guess it worked, didn’t it?
- Yeah, of course it did.
You’re never wrong, are you?
How you feelin’? Huh?
I’ve felt better.
What did you do to me?
Next time it’s your turn. Okay?
Yeah.
Yeah, you got that right.
Okay, these are so your eyes can focus
in the breathing fluid.
How’s that feel?
There it is.
If you can’t see,
you can’t disarm the bomb. Right?
Okay, with this much weight,
you’re gonna fall like a brick.
We still got about an hour,
so we should get there in plenty of time.
When you get down there,
all you gotta do is cut one wire,
drop the weights
and come on home.
- Hand me that wrench, will ya?
- Maybe I oughta check and see--
Yeah, that’s a good place.
This is loose.
I’ll fix that up.
Bud,
you don’t have to do this.
Somebody’s gotta do it.
It doesn’t have to be you.
Who, then?
So, what, I can...
hear you, but...
I can’t talk, right?
The fluid prevents the larynx
from making sound-- Excuse me.
- It’ll feel a little strange.
- Yeah, no shit.
I gotta warn you all...
I’m a pretty lousy typist.
The moment of truth.
- Come on. Let’s go.
- Let’s go.
Easy.
Okay.
I need it in the front a little bit.
Thank you.
Got it.
- Set.
- Clamp.
Okay, let’s rock and roll.
Crack it.
Headset. Headset, please.
- Okay?
- Relax now, Bud. Just relax.
- Bud. Watch me.
- Relax now, Bud.
- Relax. It’s okay.
- Okay? Watch me.
Don’t hold your breath.
Take it in.
Just let yourself take it in.
- That’s it.
- Oh, man.
Don’t hold your breath, now.
Take it in. There you go.
Don’t hold your breath.
Take it in. That’s it.
There you go.
- Bud! This is not normal!
- Hold him! Hold him!
This is normal. It’ll pass in a second.
It’s perfectly normal.
- This is normal?
- It’s perfectly normal.
We all breathed liquid for nine months, Bud.
Your body will remember.
That’s it. That’s it.
- Perfectly normal.
- Christ, he’s breathin’ it.
Give me that.
Can you hear me?
- There he goes. He’s got it.
- Yes.
- Okay, Bud.
- That’s it.
Try your keypad.
Right.
I already have.
- Okay. Let’s go.
- Great.
- Okay.
- That’s okay. I got it.
I got it.
- Okay, Hippy, you got that?
- Hold on, Jammer.
- Okay, Bud.
- Easy. Easy.
Watch out. Watch his side.
Watch the back.
Careful.
I rigged in Little Geek’s chip
the same as Big Geek.
It should take you straight there.
All you have to do is hang on.
- What’s his depth?
- 3,200 feet.
Your depth is 3,200 feet.
You’re doing fine.
You’d better watch out for crane wreckage.
You should be almost to it.
- 4,800 feet. It’s official.
- Yeah.
Bud, according to Monk here, you just
set a record for the deepest suit dive.
Bet you didn’t think you’d be doing this
when you got up this morning, huh?
One mile down. Still grinnin’.
8,500 feet.
8,500 feet, Bud.
Everything okay?
Ask him about pressure effects.
Tremors, vision problems, euphoria.
Ensign Monk wants to know
how you feel.
It’s starting.
It hits the nervous system first.
Keep talking Lindsey.
Let him hear your voice.
Okay, Bud, your depth is 8,900 feet.
- You’re doing fine.
- No, Lindsey.
Talk to him.
Bud.
There are some...
some things I need to say.
It’s hard for me, you know.
It’s not easy
being a cast-iron bitch.
Takes discipline
and years of training.
A lot of people don’t appreciate that.
Jesus, I’m sorry I can’t
tell you these things to your face.
I have to wait till
you’re alone in the dark,
freezing, and there’s
10,000 feet of water between us.
I’m sorry. I’m rambling.
Comin’ up on the big ten thou.
12,000 feet. Jesus!
- I don’t believe he’s doin’ this!
- Hippy!
Shut up! What’s wrong with you?
Bud, how are you doing?
Signal’s fading.
No. No, Bud,
I’m not going away. I’m right here.
Kill everything we don’t need. Catfish,
knock out those exterior lights. Now! Go!
Run it through the digital processor.
Cook it as much as you can.
I am right here with you, Bud.
Bud, this is Lindsey.
Please.
I’m right here with you.
Okay? So, try and stay calm.
I’m right here. All right?
Bud?
He’s losing it.
Talk to him.
- Keep him with us.
- Coming up on 16,000.
Bud, it’s the pressure.
All right?
You have to listen to my voice.
You have to try. Concentrate.
All right?
Just listen to my voice. Please.
17,000 feet.
Christ Almighty,
this is insane.
Bud, I’m not getting anything.
- Whoa, whoa-- Oh, come on. No.
- What?
- Little Geek just folded.
- Oh, Jesus.
He can still make it.
Bud,
I know how alone you feel.
Alone in all that...
cold...
blackness.
But, I’m there in the dark with you.
Oh, Bud, you’re not alone.
Oh, God.
Do you remember that time...
You were pretty drunk.
You probably don’t remember.
But the power went out in that
little apartment we had on Orange Street.
We were staring at that one little candle
and I said something really dumb, like,
“That candle is me,” like...
like every one of us is out there
alone in the dark in this life.
And you just...
you just lit up another candle
and put it beside mine...
and you said, “No. See, that’s me.
That’s me.”
We stared at the two candles, and then...
Well, if you remember any of this,
I’m sure you remember the next part.
But there are two candles in the dark.
I’m with you.
I’ll always be with you, Bud.
I promise that.
How you doin’, podner?
You still with us?
Come back.
You talk to us, Buddy boy.
- Come on.
- Bud.
Bud?
Now, come on.
You hangin’ in there?
You have to talk to me, Bud. Please.
I need to know if you’re okay.
You see--
You see a light?
What kind of light, Bud?
He’s hallucinating badly.
- He made it.
- Oh, my God.
Oh, man.
Okay, Bud,
we’ll go step by step.
Remove the detonator housing
by unscrewing it counterclockwise.
All right, Bud,
you have to cut the ground wire,
not the lead wire.
It’s the blue wire
with the white stripe.
Not, I repeat,
not the black wire
with the yellow stripe.
- Yes!
- Quiet! Quiet. Save your air.
Bud, give me a reading
off your liquid oxygen gauge.
What?
- Took him 30 minutes just to get down there!
- Bud, do you hear me?
You drop your weights
and start back now, Bud!
That gauge could be wrong!
Do you hear me?
Just drop your weights and start back now.
Your gauge could be wrong!
You drop your weights
and start back now!
No, you won’t stay there!
Do you hear me? You drop your weights.
You can breathe shallow!
Do you hear me?
Bud, please! Listen to me,
please! Goddamn it!
You dragged me back from the bottomless pit!
You can’t leave me here alone now! Please.
Oh, God, Virgil, please.
Please.
I love you.
Howdy.
How you guys doin’?
...attempts to convene a summit
between heads of state have collapsed--
Soviet buildup of tanks and aircraft have--
All citizens to stay on their jobs,
restrict unnecessary travel--
- We had moments ago an unprovoked attack...
- Holy shit.
Across the country, National Guard units
have been mobilized,
and also defense volunteer staff
have been called to full-time duty.
You watch our TV.
That’s what you’re tellin’ me...
that you know
what’s goin’ on up there?
Seismologists worldwide are reporting
an enormous disturbance...
throughout the world’s oceans
which apparently began about 15 minutes ago.
They are acoustic shock waves, like tsunamis,
but with no apparent seismological source.
The waves are propagating toward
the shorelines of every continent.
Dr. Berg, would you please,
based on the--
Young lady. Young lady, listen to me.
We don’t know what’s going on yet.
We don’t have a clue.
The horizon has already grown dark.
People are running everywhere.
It’s... it’s sheer panic.
Stay on me!
The wave-- The wave is, I don’t know,
maybe 1,000 feet high already.
Getting bigger
as I’m watching.
Still miles out.
Oh, my God.
- Get outta here!
- We’re staying!
Give it to me, then!
I don’t even know if I’m still broadcasting.
I can’t be sure.
I’ll just keep going as long as I can.
- Get out of the way!
- A thousand--
You guys are doing this.
You guys are doing this, right?
You can control water.
That’s your technology.
But why are you doin’ this?
Okay.
Okay, that’s enough.
I get the point!
How do you know...
they’re really gonna do it?
Where do you get off passin’ judgment on us?
You can’t be sure.
How do you know?
You could have done it.
Why didn’t you?
Deepcore, do you read?
This is Benthic Explorer. Over.
Do you hear, Deepcore?
Deepcore, do you read?
Do you read me, Deepcore?
This is Benthic Explorer. Over.
Hell, yes, we read.
Good of you to join us.
- Copy, Deepcore. Hey, I’ve got ’em!
- How’s that storm up there?
Well, it’s strange. It just sort of
blew itself out all of a sudden.
Hell, son, you better get
a line down to us.
We’re in moderately
poor shape down here.
We lost seven people,
includin’ Bud.
And we’re
about out of O₂,
so whatever you’re gonna do,
you better do it fast.
You boys make up your mind
how to get us out of here yet?
They’re talking about flying in a DSRV
from Norfolk.
- Just wish I could’ve seen it.
- Okay, how long is that gonna take?
How do you stop
a half-mile high tidal wave in--
Hey.
Hey. Hey, it’s Bud!
That’s impossible.
No, it’s not.
- Do you hear, Deepcore? Do you read?
- Yes!
Wait. Wait. Wait.
We’ve got a message from Bud.
- Bud?
- What’s it say?
Here.
It says “Virgil Brigman back on the air.”
Yes!
“Have some... new friends down here.”
“Guess they’ve been here a while.”
“They’ve left us alone, but it bothers them
to see us hurting each other.”
“Getting out of hand.”
“They sent a message.
Hope you got it.”
I’d say that’s a big 10-4, Jack.
“They want us
to grow up a bit
“and put away childish things.”
”Of course,
it’s just a suggestion.”
Looks like you boys
might be out of business.
What the hell’s goin’ on?
- One Night, get to sonar.
- Good God Almighty.
Fellas,
I’m gettin’ some
awful big readings here.
- Something’s coming up the wall.
- What is it?
Whatever it is, it’s major!
Something’s definitely
going on down there.
Active is pinging back something really big.
It’s huge.
- And it’s coming up right underneath us.
- Where?
Where? It’s everywhere.
There! Starboard bow.
This is the Benthic Explorer.
There! Look!
Look!
Help, Cat.
We should be dead.
We didn’t decompress.
They must’ve done something to us.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, I think you could say that.
Hi, Brigman.
Hello, Mrs. Brigman.